<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<schemalist gettext-domain="terminal-tiler">
  <schema id="org.gnome.shell.extensions.terminal-tiler"
          path="/org/gnome/shell/extensions/terminal-tiler/">

    <key name="tile-new-terminal" type="as">
      <default><![CDATA[['<Super>Return']]]></default>
      <summary>Spawn / add a terminal to the focused monitor's batch, or summon it</summary>
      <description>Opens a terminal full-screen on the focused monitor, or adds another and re-divides the monitor into equal vertical columns. If a stray terminal is focused, it is absorbed into the batch instead. If the monitor already has a batch but it is not the focused window, the whole group is raised to the front and focused instead.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="minimize-terminal-group" type="as">
      <default><![CDATA[['<Super><Primary>Return']]]></default>
      <summary>Toggle (minimise / restore) the focused monitor's terminal batch</summary>
      <description>If any terminal in the batch on the focused window's monitor is still open, minimises the whole group at once; if they are all minimised, brings them all back to the front and focuses them. The batch also minimises and restores as a unit when any single member is minimised or restored.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="move-terminal-left" type="as">
      <default><![CDATA[['<Super>Left']]]></default>
      <summary>Move the focused terminal one position towards the start of its group</summary>
      <description>If the focused window belongs to a monitor's batch, swaps it with the previous member (the column to its left, or the row above it) and re-flows the group. Does nothing if it is already first or not in a batch.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="move-terminal-right" type="as">
      <default><![CDATA[['<Super>Right']]]></default>
      <summary>Move the focused terminal one position towards the end of its group</summary>
      <description>If the focused window belongs to a monitor's batch, swaps it with the next member (the column to its right, or the row below it) and re-flows the group. Does nothing if it is already last or not in a batch.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="maximize-terminal" type="as">
      <default><![CDATA[['<Super>Up']]]></default>
      <summary>Maximise the focused terminal over its group (hide the column division)</summary>
      <description>Grows the focused terminal to fill the whole monitor work area, covering its column peers, so one terminal is temporarily full-screen without leaving the batch. The peers stay alive behind it; the division comes back via unmaximize-terminal, or whenever the group is minimised.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="unmaximize-terminal" type="as">
      <default><![CDATA[['<Super>Down']]]></default>
      <summary>Restore the focused monitor's terminal batch to its column division</summary>
      <description>Undoes maximize-terminal: re-flows the batch on the focused window's monitor back into equal columns/rows. Does nothing if the monitor's batch is not currently maximised.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="terminal-command" type="s">
      <default>'terminator'</default>
      <summary>Command used to launch a new terminal</summary>
      <description>Parsed with shell quoting rules and spawned when the keybinding needs a new terminal window.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="terminal-wm-class" type="s">
      <default>'terminator'</default>
      <summary>Substring matched (case-insensitive) against a window's WM_CLASS to decide whether it is a terminal</summary>
      <description>Used both to recognise a newly spawned terminal window and to decide whether a focused window should be absorbed into the batch.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="orientation" type="s">
      <default>'columns'</default>
      <summary>Tiling orientation</summary>
      <description>'columns' = side-by-side vertical splits (full height each). 'rows' = stacked horizontal splits (full width each).</description>
    </key>

  </schema>
</schemalist>
